John Curtis and Mary Snell Smith Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence, 1837-1873; Series I
  - Family Correspondence
    - Extended family to others
      - Asa and Polly Smith to daughters, 1844 Dec 5 (Box 3, Folder 129)
      - Laura S. Parkhurst to sisters Marcia and Lucia, 1840 Jul 19- 1842 Jul 18 (Box 3, Folder 130)
      - Laura S. Parkhurst to sisters Marcia and Lucia, 1842 Aug 19- 1843 Nov 9 (Box 3, Folder 131)
      - Laura S. Parkhurst to sisters Marcia and Lucia, 1843 Dec 17- 1849 Jan 21 (Box 3, Folder 132)
      - Laura S. Parkhurst to sisters Marcia and Lucia, 1849 Mar 4- 1850 May 19 (Box 3, Folder 133)
      - Lucia, Marcia and Laura to parents, 1844 Jul 15- 1851 Feb 14 (Box 3, Folder 134)
      - Sarah White (sister) to Polly W. Smith, 1845 Jan 31 (Box 3, Folder 135)
      - Misc. letters between family members, 1845 Feb 17- 1850 Apr 22 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Non family correspondence
    - Letters to JCS
      - Clark, L.S, 1846 Dec 15- 1851 Sep 18 (Box 3, Folder 137)
      - Farr, Jonathan Jr., 1844 Dec 18 (Box 3, Folder 137)
      - "B.F.H.", 1846 Feb 22- 1851 Mar 3 (Box 3, Folder 137)
      - Morse, Esther, 1869 Mar 29 (Box 3, Folder 137)
      - Taylor, Rev E.W, 1845 Apr 12- 1851 Jul (Box 3, Folder 138)
      - Townshend, Harriet, 1873 Mar 12 (Box 3, Folder 138)
      - Ward, N., 1847 Nov 15 (Box 3, Folder 138)
      - Whiting, Lyman, 1845 Oct 29 (Box 3, Folder 138)
      - Wight, Daniel, 1848 Feb 16 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Letters to MSS
      - Alen, Lizzie, 1862 Apr 2 (Box 3, Folder 139)
      - Cope, E. Mrs., 1862 Sep 11 (Box 3, Folder 139)
      - Green, J.E., 1862 Jul 16- 1864 Dec 29 (Box 3, Folder 139)
      - Hayward, Esther W, 1862 Jul 4 (Box 3, Folder 139)
      - Howland, S. S., 1862 Dec 11 (Box 3, Folder 140)
      - Howland, W.W., 1868 Aug 19 (Box 3, Folder 140)
      - Hyde, Hattie L., 1863 Jun 14 (Box 3, Folder 140)
      - Lakewood, Sarah, 1869 Feb 2 (Box 3, Folder 140)
      - Nash, N.S., 1862 Feb 27- 1863 Jun 28 (Box 3, Folder 140)
      - Townshend, Harriet, 1872 May 2, 1872 May 20, 1872 Jul 10, 1872 Jul 26, 1872 Aug 8 (Box 3, Folder 141)
      - Townshend, Harriet, 1872 Sep 4, 1872 Nov 5, 1872 Dec 18, 1873 Jan 1, 1873 Jan 6 (Box 3, Folder 142)
      - Townshend, Harriet, 1873 Jan 24 (Box 3, Folder 143)
      - Townshend, Harriet, 1873 Mar 7 (Box 3, Folder 143)
      - Townshend, Harriet, 1873 Apr 6 (Box 3, Folder 143)
      - Townshend, Harriet (letter and fragment) (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Letters to JCS and MSS
      - Cleveland, Charles, 1862 Jun 17 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      - Cleveland, Lucy F and Charles, 1862 Oct 19 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      - Hillis, H, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      - Spalding, Levi, 1862 Sep 9 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      - Tracy, Dr. Stephen, 1869 Apr 27 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      - Townshend, Harriet, 1872 Nov 5,17 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      - Letters to Laura P. Smith, 1872 Apr 18- Jul 4 (Box 3, Folder 145)
      - Letters to Eunice M. Smith (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - M. Elizabeth Childs, 1866 Jan 9 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - M. Elizabeth Childs, 1866 Oct 21 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Mary W. Godding, 1866 Feb 16 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Mary W. Godding, 1867 Dec 25 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - W.W. Howland, 1866 Dec 5 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - W.W. Howland, 1868 Jan 27 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Amelia Lockwood, 1869 May 11 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Mt. Holyoke Seminary Class Song, 1865 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Letter to Mary E. Smith, 1869 Jul 4 (Box 3, Folder 147)
      - Daniel Poor to Rev. Galie, 1854 Dec 25 (Box 3, Folder 148)
- Letterbooks, 1853-1868; Series II
  Correspondence in the letterbooks was arranged according to system. For instance, one letterbook contains correspondence between John Curtis Smith and his siblings and parents and Andover classmates, during the 1840's; another contains only letters written by children Thomas, Eunice, Laura, William and Henry to their parents, and letters from the childrens' caregivers between 1861 and 1864, etc. Within the letterbooks, letters are organized, chronologically, by correspondent (e.g., within one letterbook, all of Thomas' letters are bound together, in chronological order, followed by Eunice's in a similar arrangement, Laura's, William's and Henry's).
  - Volume 2
    - Section A. Snell Family members to MSS & JCS regarding arrival of children in U.S., 1853 Sep 27- 1854 Apr (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section B. Susan & Cyrus Mills to MSS & JCS regarding trip to America with Thomas and Eunice Smith., 1853 Dec 26- 1854 Mar 18 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section C. Thomas Smith, shipboard journal., 1853 Dec 21- 1854 Feb 11 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section D. Eunice Smith shipboard journal., 1853 Dec 21- 1854 Mar 4 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section E. Susam Mills' account of voyage to America, 1854 Mar 30 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section F. Shipboard journals of Thomas & Eunice Smith, 1854 Mar 3- May 15 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section G. Letters concerning arrival of Thomas & Eunice Smith in U.S., 1854 May 17- 25 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section H. Thomas & Eunice Smith's journal letters and letter from Eliza Halleck, to MSS and JCS, 1854 May 19- Sep 20 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section I. Letters from Thomas and Eunice, and from Eliza Halleck and her children to MSS and JCS, 1854 Nov 24- Dec 30 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section J. Letters from Thomas and Eunice, and from Eliza Halleck to Susan MIlls, 1854 Jun 20-1855 Feb 26 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section K. Letters from Eliza Halleck, Ebenezer Snell, Susan Mills and Eunice Smith to MSS and JCS, 1855 Jan 1- Mar 3 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section L. Hand-drawn map of New England by Thomas Smith, c.1855 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section M. Letters from Susan Mills, Halleck family and Eunice Smith to MSS and JCS, 1855 Apr 13- May 22 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section N. Letters from Halleck relatives and one letters from Eunice Smith, to MSS and JCS, 1855 Jul 2- Jul 27 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section O. Letters from Halleck relatives and Eunice Smith to JCS and MSS, 1855 Sep 5- Oct 20 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section P. Letters from Halleck and Snell relatives, Susan Mills, and Thomas Smith to MSS and JCS and from Eliza Halleck to Susan Mills, 1855 Sep 7- 1856 Jan 15 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section Q. Letters from Thomas and Eunice Smith, Halleck and Snell relatives to MSS and JCS, 1856 Jan 1- Mar 28 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section R. Letters from Thomas and Eunice Smith, Thomas Snell (MSS cousin) and Halleck relatives to MSS and JCS, 1856 Apr 15- May 9 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section S. Letters from nieces, Eliza Halleck Rouse and Fannie Halleck Hazeltine to MSS, 1856 Jul 27- Aug 26 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Section T. Letters from Thomas and Eunice Smith and Eliza Halleck to MSS and JCS, 1856 Jul 28- Aug 26 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Section U. Map of Minnesota and house plan from Eben Snell (brother) to MSS, also letters from Thomas and Eunice Smith and Eliza Halleck to MSS and JCS, and small watercolor painting of a hummingbird, 1856 Jun 24- Oct 8 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Volume 3.
    - Letters from MSS, JCS, siblings, cousins and other relatives to William H. Smith, including a letter from Henry H. Smith to sister Mary, and ABCFM certificates and donation receipts, 1858 Jan 9- 1865 Feb 2 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Volume 4
    - Section A. Letter from John S. Green to MSS, 1861 Dec 4 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section B. Letters from Gilsum, N.H. relatives and acquaintances to MSS and JCS, 1860 Dec 18- 1864 Dec 9 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section C. Letters from friends in Winchendon, Mass., including Mary W. Gooding, J.B. Hyde and Sarah Hyde, to MSS and JCS, 1861 Jan 15- 1863 Dec 22 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section D. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS and JCS, including Monson Academy programs and song and letter from Monson Academy principal Mr. Grout, 1861 Mar 5- 1862 Aug 16 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section E. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS and JCS, written while at Amherst College, 1862 Sep ?- 1863 Jul 25 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section F. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS & JCS written while at Amherst College., 1863 Sep 28- 1864 Aug 19 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section G. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS & JCS, written while at Amherst College, 1864 Sep 2- Dec 20 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section H. Letters from Eunice Smith to MSS & JCS, written principally from Gilsum, N.H., 1860 Dec 8- 1863 Jul 27 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section I. Letters from Eunice Smith to MSS & JCS, written while at Mt. Holyoke Seminary, 1863 Sep 12- 1864 Dec 28 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section J. Letters from Laura Smith to MSS & JCS. written from Winchendon, Mass., 1860 Dec 27- 1863 Oct 3 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section K. Letters from Laura Smith to MSS & JCS, written from Brookfield, Mass., 1863 Dec 14- 1864 Aug 18 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section L. Letters from Laura Smith to MSS & JCS. written from Mt. Holyoke Seminary., 1864 Sep 24- Dec 20 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section M. Letters from William Smith to MSS & JCS. written from Gilsum, N.H., ?1860 Nov 30- 1862 Nov 25 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section N. Letters from Henry Smith to JCS & MSS, written from Winchendon & Brookfield, Mass., 1861 Aug 21- 1864 Dec 1 (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section O. Hannah M. Fish to MSS & JCS with house diagram, also Thomas Smith financial accounts & his "vital statistics," & "Plan of Mr. Hyde's house", 1861 ca. Mar - 1862 Sep (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - Section P. 'Cure for Cholera' (handwritten), letter from S.A.B. to MSS, 7 October, no year, and ca. 12 fabric samples pasted on back cover.", No date (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Volume 5
    - Section A. Letters from Thomas Smith to Mary E. Smith (sister), 1862 Jun 22- 1864 Oct 19 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Section B. Letters from Eunice Smith to Mary E. Smith (sister), 1861 Mar 12- Jul 2 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Section C. Letters from Laura Smith to Mary E. Smith (sister), including a "dialogue" with President Lincoln, also letter from Hannah Fish to Mary E. Smith, 1861 Mar 20- Jul 2 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Section D. Letters from William Smith to Mary E. Smith (sister), 1861 Nov 18- [1864?] Oct 14 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Section E. Letters from Henry Smith to Mary E. Smith (sister, 1861 Nov 14- 1865 Feb13 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Section F. Letters from Hattie Hyde, including one from Hattie Hyde & Laura Smith (sister), 1861 Nov 18-1864 Oct 19 (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Section G. Miscellaneous letters to Mary E. Smith, including from Samuel F. Green, Mr. and Mrs. Sanders, "Joseph" (servant). Includes also patriotic stickers and address label., 1863 Feb 3- Feb 21 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Volume 6
    - Section A. Letters from children's caregivers to MSS & JCS, including from Hannah M. Fish & Elisha S. Fish, 1864 Jan 2- Aug 29 (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - Section B. Letters from children's caregivers to MSS & JCS, including Mary W. Godding, Sarah H. Hyde, and Mary Fish Snell., 1864 Aug- 1865 Mar 30 (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - Section C. Letters from cousins in Gilsum, N.H. who are children's caregivers to MSS & JCS, including from Janette Landon Fish, Elisha Fish, and Hannah M. Fish., 1865 Nov 1- 1866 Apr 19 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Volume 7
    - Section A. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS & JCS, written while at Amherst College., 1865 Jan 14- Aug 29 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section B. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS & JCS, written while at Amherst College., 1865 Sep 12- 1866 Jun 4 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section C. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS & JCS, 1864 Jun 29- 1866 Dec 29 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section D. Letters from Eunice Smith to MSS & JCS, written from Mt. Holyoke Seminary., 1864 Feb 3- 1865 Nov 6 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section E. Letters from Eunice Smith to MSS & JCS, 1865 Dec 2- 1866 Dec 12 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section F. Letter from Mary W. Godding to MSS, 1866 Dec 12 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section G. Letters from Laura Smith to MSS & JCS, from Mt. Holyoke Seminary, 1865 Jan 3- Jul 1 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section H. Letters from Laura Smith to MSS & JCS, 1866 Jul 27- Dec 9 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section I. Letters from William Smith to MSS & JCS, including letter to Thomas Smith (brother), 1866 Jan 4- Dec 29 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section J. Letters from Henry H. Smith to MSS & JCS., 1865 Jan 2- 1866 Nov 16 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - Section K. Letters from Mary Smith to MSS & JCS, including letter to Thomas Smith (brother), 1865 Mar 1- 1866 Dec 21 (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Volume 8
    - Section A. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS & JCS, 1866 Jan 8- 1867 Sep 9 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section B. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS & JCS, from Andover Seminary, 1867 Sep 19- Dec 21 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section C. Letters from Thomas Smith to MSS & JCS, from Andover Seminar., 1868 Jan 4- Oct 17 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section D. Letters from Eunice Smith to MSS & JCS, including letters to siblings, 1867 Feb 1- Dec 27 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section E. Letters from Eunice Smith to MSS & JCS, including letters to siblings, 1868 Jan- Oct 6 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section F. Letters from Laura Smith to MSS & JCS, 1867 Jan 12- Dec 26 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section G. Letters from Laura Smith to MSS & JCS, 1865 Jan 2- 1868 Aug 16 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section H. Letters from William Smith to MSS & JCS, 1867 Jan 18- 1868 Oct 15 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section I. Letters from Henry H. Smith to MSS & JCS, 1867 Jan 14- 1868 Oct 1 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Section J. Letters from Mary E. Smith to MSS & JCS, including note from Laura Smith, 1866 Jan 19- 1868 Sep 2 (Box 6, Folder 155)
- Journals, 1841-1865; Series III
  - JC Smith
    - Begins on board "Brenda" to Ceylon, 1841 Oct 14- 1842 Dec (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - On board "Sea King" to Madras, 1860 Nov 8- 1861 Mar (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - On land, 1861 Mar 12- May 15 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Memorandum book: daily journal kept by Smith with detailed accounts of his work in Ceylon, 1861 Jun- 1865 Jul 12 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - Mary E. Smith
    - On board the "Lord Wardon", 1865 Jan 18- [1865 Dec?] (Box 7, Folder 159)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1841-1866; Series IV
  - Childrens' expense accounts, 1863-1866 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Fabric scraps, 1861-1863 (Box 7, Folder 161)
  - Blank stationery, fragments, 1841 (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - Laura Smith's notebook, 1861 Dec 18- 1861 Dec 27 (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - Family photographs, 1869-1872, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - Detailed biographical sketches of Smith family members, and an essay about the collection, including information about the families that cared for the Smith children, written by Elizabeth C. Stevens., 2008 (Box 7, Folder 165)